Did you think that Ree would be dead?
>> No. No. We hoped uh but there weren't a
lot of scenarios that we went through
where he may be available.
>> How do you envision him fitting in
obviously after Kavon?
>> Yeah, Reese. He's uh Arll is a versatile
player and we're going to play inside
backer will linebacker. Our defense is
pretty flexible. you know, positionless,
you might call it, and have an
opportunity to move those guys around,
but he'll line up uh he'll line up next
to uh Germaine and uh and he'll be he'll
be in the A gap, the B gap, the C gap,
the D gap off the edge. He'll be moving
around with all of our guys. Uh Abdul
and Brian and Kavon uh and and Tmaine.
He'll be running he'll be running games
and picks and stunts and just things
like that passing situations and he's
good in coverage as well. He's a
versatile player. He's a young player.
Uh he's gotten better every single year
playing off the ball and on the ball. So
he does both. Probably why he was our
highest rated player, non-quarterback
player in the draft. Uh he's he's an
exciting player. We are fired up to
have. You
>> mentioned Kavon's name. Is there does
this give you flexibility to potentially
move on from him or you plan to keep on
tip it up?
We keep all the good players as much as
we can, right?
>> Yep.
>> We love K.
>> Yeah.
>> What uh you know, what is uh Reese's
upside as a pass rusher?
>> Oh, it's tremendous. It's tremendous. I
mean, again, he's just scratching the
surface. You see, you know, the size,
the length, the traits. Um and again,
like coach was talking about just the
the versatility that the player has and
how we can use him with some of the
pieces that we already have. um you
know, we're not going to necessarily
have to ask him to win off the edge.
We've got guys that can do that. So, um
we have a phenomenal defensive staff and
you know, they're going to find creative
ways to use him.
>> I can just tell you that we're watching
Pro Day, right? And uh standing there
watching, he lines up on the edge in a
drill where you time him coming off the
edge, the quickness, and it was shocking
to see how quickly he goes from point A
to point B out of his stance. So,
>> uh there's there's really nothing he
can't do physically. He's going to turn
>> in in like August 30th. Yeah. And Yeah.
>> He's a young player. It's all upside for
him.
>> Yeah. He's one of the guys again playing
on one of the best defenses in America
that I mean shows up you're like wow wow
plays. Wow plays.
>> Was it tempting with Caleb D sitting
there at 10 to choose him and why did
you go with Minoa?
>> Uh we stuck with the board. We stuck
with the board and CeCe is a another
20-year-old believe it or not. you know,
he'll be 21 in June. So, we got two
young players that we're fired up about.
Um, but a powerful young man with with
tremendous athleticism and size and I
don't know if you guys saw his uh
interview there on TV, you know, they
asked him, you know, what he should tell
Jackson and that was that's the type of
kid he is. So again, to get those two
young young men that have, you know,
size and athleticism and and the makeup
that we desire and the fact that we know
that we're going to have those guys
under contract for 5 years to add the
some of the young foundational pieces
that we already have. I mean, it's it's
really exciting. Really exciting.
>> At guard,
>> you start him. You view him as a guard.
>> We're going to put him we're going to
put him inside at guard. He can
certainly play tackle. Um, you know,
sometimes we call these schools and get
some of the films. you know, they have
two really good rushers down there at
Miami and Mezador and Bane. And, you
know, to watch the practice film of I
mean, he's going against NFL dudes on a
daily basis and doing a really good job.
It was pretty impressive. So, he could
certainly always, you know, bump back
out to to tackle at any point. Um, we're
going to start him at guard
>> back. That was something you heard about
him that could possibly need back
surgery. Like, where do you guys stand
on that?
>> Yeah, we're comfortable with it. We're
comfortable with it and we're fortunate
that the uh the former trainer from the
University of Miami is now one of our
trainers. So, you know, we have somebody
that had been with him for his entire
time um at Miami and lived with him
through, you know, the process. It was
an injury that occurred in the&m game
and um we're certainly comfortable with
it. [snorts]
>> Does that mean you don't think he's
going to need surgery or it just might
be something? You'll see how it kind of
works out
>> right now. He's he's fine. Yeah, he's
he's good right now.
>> John, with with Mommy Noah, I mean, back
at the owner's meetings, you said
offensive line is still a work in
progress. What does this do for you?
Work in progress.
>> It advances it, you know. Uh we'll have
to finish it off at practice, you know,
for the next couple weeks and put it all
together. But uh it's it it makes us a
lot more stout. It uh it's it's two
picks that strengthen us down the
middle, down the middle of our offense,
down the middle of our defense. I mean,
these are two these are great players.
These are two top five players in this
draft in our opinion. You couldn't do
any better. I think Joe probably ran
about a zillion mocks. I mean, it's
maybe that's
like a high number, but maybe it was a
couple million. And uh this one didn't
come up. This was not one that was
really anticipated. That just shows you
that uh you know reality is is stranger
than fiction is stranger than reality.
Reality is stranger than fiction.
[laughter]
It's one of the fun.
>> You know, you know what I'm saying.
>> This is this is exciting. This is not
expected. This is something that's
really a great a great opportunity for
us.
>> How did um this is the first time I get
to talk to you since since the Dexter
trade. So, how did that change your
overall approach to this process?
>> Uh, the only thing that changed is we
had another, you know, premium pick, you
know, with the 10th, we were able to
get, you know, two good players in in
the top 10 of our draft. And to get two
players that we had ranked where we had
them ranked, um, you know, is really
going to help us. And, you know, again,
that's before we traded him and we knew
maybe what the compensation was going to
be, we were deep into draft prep and we
had an idea what that pick would mean to
us. Uh maybe not to the extent that it
actually ended up, you know, the way it
played out. Um but we we knew we were
going to get two good players if if we
did have to move him.
>> Did like when you were going through the
trade, did you see CC there or
>> uh we we probably didn't anticipate him
go, you know, again, tackles go
relatively early. So, you know, the fact
that by time, you know, we anticipated
two tackles going by the time, you know,
we got to 10. So, however that played
out and it it played out that they went
nine and 10 and then that was, you know,
we we figured Cleveland was and they
ended up moving back. So, once it, you
know, once it came to that, we were a
little bit nervous. We weren't sure, you
know, which way they were going to go.
So, you know, worked out well for us
>> to trade down, you know, I mean, I mean,
you seem very happy with these players,
but maybe, you know,
>> we we had Yeah, we we had an opportunity
um at 10 to get out. Um, but you know,
just you know, where we had the player
rank, we stuck with our board, we're so
fired up with who we got at five and
then to follow it up with with CC at 10
just didn't make any sense to to try to
get cute and do anything else.
>> I realize you're always looking for the
best available player, but after you get
an impact player for the defense at
five, is it a natural tendency to lean
towards offense at 10 to try to make a
difference there? Is that a factor in
the back?
>> Yeah. And we we probably coach will tell
you we went over our list of 10 players.
I mean, the last two weeks we've we've
stared at it. We've looked at it. We've
adjusted it. We've watched more film,
got together, watched more film, got the
coaches more, you know, we we've done it
a zillion times. So, we just it was it
was the way we had it. We were very
confident and we just it made it real
easy. We were just going to follow the
board in terms of, you know, if it
worked out and it was two offensive
guys, that would have been okay. If it
was two defensive, that would have been
okay. But we were just going in, we had
an opportunity to get two of our top 10
players in the draft regardless of
position that were going to help, you
know, help us continue to build this
thing.
>> John, obviously the best Giants teams
have had dominant pass rushers. I'm
curious if you think this has got the
potential to be a dominant pass rush
now.
>> Absolutely. I mean, I I think it's
pretty dominant pass rush off the edges
already. We had three practices this
week with those guys and and seeing
those guys, seeing Abdul, seeing being
seeing Kavon, seeing Brian, I mean, it's
it's it's eye opening. That's eye
opening. I haven't seen those kind of
guys, you know, for a while in the
practice field. Those those kind of
talented guys. Now we had another guy
into that mix. I mean
>> I mean you just get you get excited. I
can't wait to can't wait to get him on
the practice field with all those guys.
Goldston, I mean he's heavy-handed guy.
>> Yeah,
>> we got some dudes, you know, we still
have work to do on our defense. You
know, we do. We still got some work to
do, but uh this this is a big step.
>> We haven't got a chance to talk to you
since the next trade. You talked you
said earlier you want to keep all the
good players. How did it get to the
point no return [snorts] with it?
>> Uh I I don't know. I mean there's a lot
of lot of factors, a lot of layers to
it. Uh I think there's the financial
part of it. There's probably family part
of it. There's probably, you know, part
time in someone's career where they say,
you know, it's just time for me to make
a change, you know, uh things like that.
So, but it was it was I I look at like a
win-win win. I think it was a win for
everybody. For us, the most important
thing was that it was a win for the
Giants. That's what we cared about the
most. We wanted Dexter to be happy, you
know, but uh we wanted the Giants to be
taken care of first. That was our
responsibility to get the 10th pick in
the draft and then to see it play out
tonight. It's pretty clear-cut that it's
a W for us. Not that it wouldn't have
been a W to keep Dexter. It sure would
have been, but that didn't turn out to
be possible. It wasn't something that,
you know, he was really prioritizing in
the end. And that's okay. Uh that's just
that's fine. He got uh an opportunity
and the Bengals got an opportunity to
get a great player and and uh you know
it's going to make their defense better.
So everybody's everybody's a winner on
this one.
>> John, um you've been at one place for so
long. Um this was your first draft war
[clears throat] with this operation. How
did it seem different to you? Did it
seem, you know, did it you know, you
haven't had two picks in the top 10
either. So
>> yeah, that was different. That was
different. We had one in 18. Now we had
two, you know, in about I don't know an
hour. [laughter] one and a half maybe.
And it was uh it was fun. It was
impressive to watch. And it's not so
much, you know, I thought I thought Joe
did a great job tonight operating, you
know, under pressure. Uh was was very
well prepared obviously and just uh just
knew what he wanted to do and was
feeling the different calls and and
communicating with everybody. We we just
thought we had a [snorts] really good
operation
>> and Joe leads the way on that and did a
great job with it. And then uh and then
the the leadup the the preparation. The
scouts the scouts were really good.
Thought the scouts were good throughout.
Great dialogue. Not always agreeing, you
know, it wasn't like everybody's on the
same page. You know, consensus is uh is
not always a great thing. Uh but we
ended up uh we ended up agreeing to uh
to to kind of agree on the on the fact
that we had we had 10 really good
players probably on that board
>> for 10 picks and we got two of our top
five at the end of the day. So I thought
the scouts were great. I thought the
coaches did a great job just really
throughout the organization. It was
really fun to be a part of it and watch
it. I was very impressed with
everything, you know, and and as much as
anything, the outcome right now. We
still have work to do. We have two more
days, but uh it's a really good start.
>> Johnny two more
>> John. Historically, I think with the
Ravens, you've taken defensive players
high on the drafts. I'm curious, how did
that philosophy mesh with looking at a
player like Reese and say, "Hey, this
kind of fits in with what I've done
before, but also with what the team
wants to do with him?" Well, it just
it's similar in the sense that o over
over the years and Joe and I had we've
had a lot of these kind of philosophical
conversations, but really what you want
to do is you want to give the draft an
opportunity to work for you and let it
come to you. You don't want to chase
picks. You want you want picks to chase
you, you know, and and give them an
opportunity to come to you. And
sometimes you got to be patient to do
that, you know, and get your board
right. Make sure you understand, you
know, you know, all the different
possibilities and and and don't uh don't
overreact to things that you hear,
things that might happen on draft night.
And I thought we did a really good job
of that. And all of a sudden, you know,
there's Arvel Ree, you know, who's
coming to us. And that's what that's
happened in. It's happened in Baltimore.
It's happened in New York a number of
times, too. I know Joe's had that
experience here as well. So, uh, it
worked out just the way you hope it
would in that situation. Doesn't always
work out that way, but it did tonight.
>> Where did you have Reank your top five?
>> Dulge at We have him number one.
>> Yeah. Nine quarterbacks. So,